Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we've got a very nerve-wracking situation for you.
我是Catherine，今天我们给大家带来一个非常紧张的场景。
That's right.
没错。
We are going to meet the in-laws.
我们要去见未来的岳父母/公婆。
Meeting the in-laws.
见未来的岳父母/公婆。
So who are in-laws?
那么，什么是“in-laws”？
These are the parents of your husband or wife.
就是你丈夫或妻子的父母。
Right.
对。
So in this case, you have the mother-in-law and your father-in-law.
所以在这种情况下，有岳母/婆婆和岳父/公公。
That's right.
没错。
We're meeting these people for the very first time.
我们是第一次见这些人。
You can imagine how nervous the man is who's meeting his future wife's parents.
你可以想象这个男人有多紧张，他要见未来妻子的父母。
Let's learn all about what they talk about in today's dialogue.
让我们来了解今天对话中他们谈论的内容。
Mother, father, I'd like to introduce you to my fiancé, Bob.
妈妈，爸爸，我想给你们介绍一下我的未婚夫，Bob。
Hello, Bob.
你好，Bob。
Welcome.
欢迎。
Thanks for having me.
谢谢你们邀请我。
Nice to meet the both of you.
很高兴见到你们两位。
I've heard so much.
我听说过很多。
So Cindy told you about bringing home her last boyfriend then.
所以Cindy告诉过你她带回家上一个男朋友的事吧。
That idiot.
那个白痴。
Shhh, Thurston.
嘘，Thurston。
You're going to scare the poor boy.
你会吓到那个可怜的小伙子的。
Come in and have a drink.
进来喝一杯吧。
Dinner will be on in just a bit.
晚餐马上就好。
What will you be having?
你想喝什么？
Whiskey, bourbon?
威士忌，波本？
Pick your poison.
选你的毒药吧。
If you have a lemonade, that'd be great.
如果有柠檬水的话，那就太好了。
Lemonade?
柠檬水？
Why, sure.
哦，当然有。
There's some in the fridge.
冰箱里有一些。
Mother makes her own lemonade from scratch.
妈妈自己从头开始做柠檬水。
It's the best.
最好喝了。
So what are your hobbies, son?
那么，你有什么爱好，孩子？
If you want, we can do some hunting tomorrow.
如果你愿意，我们明天可以去打猎。
I've just picked up a new rifle I've been meaning to try out.
我刚买了一把新步枪，一直想试试。
It should be a real hoot.
应该会很有趣。
Um, I'm not really, uh, I don't really hunt.
嗯，我不太，呃，我不太打猎。
You don't hunt?
你不打猎？
Well, I'll beat damn.
好吧，真见鬼。
Bob is an animal rights activist.
Bob是个动物权利活动家。
He doesn't believe in harming animals.
他不相信伤害动物。
Dinner's ready.
晚餐准备好了。
Let's go out to the patio where the pig is roasting.
我们去院子里吧，那里正在烤猪。
Roast pig?
烤猪？
I'm a vegetarian.
我是素食主义者。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a very awkward situation.
真是个尴尬的局面。
I think they might have a little bit of a problems in the future.
我想他们未来可能会有点问题。
Yeah, there's there are a lot of cultural differences between the characters, the son-in-law
是的，角色之间有很多文化差异，这个女婿
and the new parents, the father.
和新父母，父亲之间。
So it's really interesting.
所以真的很有趣。
Why don't we start off by looking at a couple of different words on language takeaway.
我们不如先看看“语言要点”中的几个单词。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
So first of all, we have the two characters, Cindy and Bob, who are getting married.
首先，我们有Cindy和Bob这两个角色，他们要结婚了。
So we call them, we call Bob, Cindy's fiance.
所以我们称Bob为Cindy的未婚夫。
Right.
对。
So my fiance.
所以我的未婚夫。
And it's, uh, it comes from French and it means to the person that you're going to get
它来自法语，意思是你将要
married to.
结婚的人。
That's right.
没错。
The person you've decided to get married to.
你决定要结婚的人。
So we say fiance.
所以我们说fiancé。
We can say the same word for a man or a woman.
这个词对男人或女人都可以用。
So he is my fiance.
所以他是我的未婚夫。
She is my fiance.
她是我的未婚妻。
Okay.
好的。
My fiance.
我的未婚夫/未婚妻。
Very good.
很好。
So Cindy introduces her fiance, Bob, to her parents and they start talking a little bit
所以Cindy把她的未婚夫Bob介绍给她的父母，他们开始聊了一会儿，
and her dad, Thurston, invites him to go do some hunting tomorrow.
她的父亲Thurston邀请他明天去打猎。
That's right.
没错。
So hunting is a sport in America and lots of places in the world where you shoot animals.
所以打猎是美国和世界上很多地方的一项运动，就是射杀动物。
Okay.
好的。
So you go in the woods, you wear brown and green colors and you shoot animals to take
所以你去树林里，穿着棕色和绿色的衣服，射杀动物，然后
them home and skin them and eat them or to keep them as trophies.
带回家剥皮吃掉，或者作为战利品保存。
All right.
好的。
So you go hunting and well, the way that you shoot these animals is you need to have a
所以你去打猎，而射杀这些动物的方式是你需要有一把
rifle.
步枪。
A rifle.
一支步枪。
So you could also call it a hunting rifle in this case.
所以在这种情况下，你也可以称之为猎枪。
A rifle is a gun, but it's a very long gun.
步枪是一种枪，但它是一种很长的枪。
Right.
对。
So it's not a little gun that you just hold in your hand.
所以它不是那种你握在手里的小枪。
It's very long.
它很长。
It'll be maybe like half a meter, a meter long.
大概有半米到一米长。
That's right.
没错。
And so oftentimes people, when they're hunting, they lie on the ground and they wait for the
所以很多时候，人们打猎时，会趴在地上等待
animals to pass and they hide themselves and then they shoot from a long distance.
动物经过，他们隐藏自己，然后从远处射击。
Right.
对。
So he's talking about hunting.
所以他在谈论打猎。
He's got a new rifle and he says, yeah, we should definitely go.
他有一把新步枪，他说，是啊，我们真该去。
It should be a real hoot.
肯定会很有趣。
Should be a real hoot.
This is a very fun spoken English phrase.
这是一个很有趣的口语短语。
It's said more by older people than by younger people.
年纪大的人比年轻人更常说。
So this is why the father says it in the dialogue.
所以这就是为什么对话中父亲会这么说。
A hoot should be a real good time, real fun.
“A hoot” 意思是玩得很开心，非常有趣。
So how can you can use this like, oh, the party last night was a real hoot.
所以你可以这样用，比如，昨晚的派对真有趣。
Yeah.
嗯。
You can say that.
你可以这么说。
You can say or she's a real hoot.
你也可以说，她真有趣。
She's really funny.
她真的很好笑。
Okay.
好的。
But it's really enjoyable.
但确实很愉快。
This is a little bit more like spoken and for used by maybe older people.
这更偏向口语，可能年纪大的人用得多。
My mother would say that I wouldn't say this.
我妈妈会这么说，但我不会。
So, oh my goodness, it was a real hoot.
所以，哦，天哪，那真有趣。
Yeah.
嗯。
All right.
好的。
So he's talking about hunting, how much fun they would have.
所以他在谈论打猎，以及他们会玩得多开心。
And unfortunately, Bob is an animal rights activist.
不幸的是，鲍勃是个动物权益活动家。
What does this mean?
这是什么意思？
So an animal rights activist is someone who is very concerned with protecting the rights
动物权益活动家是指非常关心保护动物权利
of animals.
的人。
So for example, if I'm an animal rights activist, maybe I will protest people who wear fur or
比如，如果我是动物权益活动家，我可能会抗议穿皮草的人，或者
perhaps I will also try and secure land for a natural wildlife preserve so that animals
我还会努力争取土地建立自然野生动物保护区，让动物
can live in the wild.
能在野外生活。
There's not houses or cars.
没有房子或汽车。
So animal rights activists are people who try to make sure that animals are protected
所以动物权益活动家是努力确保动物
from human beings.
免受人类伤害的人。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
And this is what Bob is.
而鲍勃就是这样的人。
So obviously Bob is not really into hunting, right?
所以显然鲍勃不太喜欢打猎，对吧？
I'm guessing no.
我猜是不喜欢。
These are two opposites.
这是两个对立面。
You have people who like to kill animals and people who want to protect the lives of animals.
有喜欢杀动物的人，也有想保护动物生命的人。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
Well, and to finish off our language takeaway, dinner is ready.
好了，为了结束我们的语言要点环节，晚餐准备好了。
So let's go out to the patio.
所以我们去露台吧。
Okay.
好的。
A patio is a space outside the house, usually in the back that's paved.
露台是房子外面的空间，通常在后面，铺有地面。
So there's like cement or bricks or some kind of tile.
比如有水泥、砖块或某种瓷砖。
And that's where you have a table and chairs or some place to sit and rest.
那里有桌子和椅子，或者可以坐和休息的地方。
This is where you have a grill.
那里有烤架。
So it's an outdoor area, but it's not grass.
所以它是一个户外区域，但不是草地。
Okay.
好的。
So it's not your backyard.
所以它不是你的后院。
Oh, it could be in your backyard.
哦，它可以在你的后院。
The patio could be in the backyard.
露台可以在后院。
That's right.
没错。
But the ground in the patio is not grass.
但露台的地面不是草地。
It's some kind of material like cement or brick or wood.
是某种材料，比如水泥、砖块或木头。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
So great words there.
这些词很棒。
Why don't we listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
我们为什么不听一遍对话，然后稍后回来进行流利度训练。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So we have three great phrases here on Fluency Builder.
所以我们在流利度训练中有三个很棒的短语。
Why don't we start off with the first one?
我们先从第一个开始吧？
So the first one, we have to go back to the very beginning of this dialogue and think
第一个，我们要回到这个对话的最开始，想想
about these people who are introducing each other for the very first time.
这些第一次互相介绍的人。
Cindy says, I want to introduce you to my fiance, Bob.
辛迪说，我想把你介绍给我的未婚夫鲍勃。
Bob says to Cindy's parents, I've heard so much.
鲍勃对辛迪的父母说，久仰大名。
I've heard so much.
久仰大名。
Okay.
好的。
So this phrase, you can usually use it when you meet somebody for the first time.
所以这个短语，你通常可以在第一次见到某人时使用。
I've heard so much about you.
久仰大名。
That's right.
没错。
So the longer version is I've heard so much about you.
所以更长的版本是“久仰大名”。
Basically you're saying, listen, Cindy talks about you a lot.
基本上你在说，听着，辛迪经常提起你。
I've heard really nice things.
我听到了很多好话。
Sometimes people like to joke.
有时候人们喜欢开玩笑。
You say, I've heard so much about you.
你说，“久仰大名。”
They say, I hope only good things.
他们会说，“希望都是好话。”
Yeah, I hope not too much.
是啊，希望没说得太多。
I hope not too much.
希望没说得太多。
So this is a very polite way to respond when someone introduces themselves.
所以这是别人自我介绍时一种非常礼貌的回应方式。
Okay.
好的。
I've heard so much about you.
久仰大名。
It's a pleasure to finally meet you.
很高兴终于见到你。
Exactly.
正是。
Okay.
好的。
So they started talking and actually Thurston offers him a drink.
所以他们开始聊天，实际上瑟斯顿给他递了一杯酒。
He says, well, what do you want?
他说，嗯，你想喝什么？
Whiskey, bourbon?
威士忌，波本？
Pick your poison.
选你的毒药。
All right.
好的。
This is one of my very favorite phrases in English.
这是我在英语里最喜欢的短语之一。
The father-in-law wants to give the new son-in-law a drink.
岳父想给新女婿一杯酒。
And there are many different options.
有很多不同的选择。
So pick your poison means pick your drink.
所以“pick your poison”意思是选你的酒。
You might hear this at a bar.
你可能会在酒吧里听到这个。
What do you want to drink?
你想喝什么？
Pick your poison.
选你的毒药。
Right.
对。
You could have whiskey, rum.
你可以喝威士忌、朗姆酒。
So usually we're just talking about alcoholic drinks.
所以通常我们只指酒精饮料。
Okay.
好的。
So you wouldn't really use this for juices or water or something like that?
所以你一般不会用它来指果汁或水之类的？
Nah.
不会。
This is for alcohol.
这是指酒精。
Okay.
好的。
So if you say pick your poison, that's for alcohol, right?
所以如果你说“pick your poison”，那是针对酒精的，对吧？
Or maybe you can ask somebody what they're drinking.
或者你可以问别人在喝什么。
You would say, what's your poison?
你会说，“你的毒药是什么？”
Yeah.
是的。
What's your poison?
你的毒药是什么？
Okay.
好的。
So poison in this case is a slang term for alcohol.
所以这里的“poison”是酒精的俚语。
Very good.
非常好。
And finally, when Cindy was talking about lemonade that her mother made, she said she
最后，当辛迪谈到她妈妈做的柠檬水时，她说她
makes it from scratch, to make something from scratch.
是“from scratch”做的，即从头开始做。
You could say, my mother makes chocolate chip cookies from scratch.
你可以说，我妈妈从头开始做巧克力曲奇。
This means not to buy something in the store, but to make it all yourself from nothing.
这意味着不是在商店里买，而是自己从零开始做。
So making lemonade from scratch means taking lemons, cutting them, taking the juice, adding
所以从头开始做柠檬水意味着拿柠檬，切柠檬，取汁，加
some sugar.
一些糖。
So you're making it from nothing.
所以你是从无到有做出来的。
You're not using some kind of kit or some kind of canned drink from the store.
你不是用某种套装或商店里的罐装饮料。
Okay.
好的。
So for example, maybe some Italians in Italy make their spaghetti from scratch with flour
比如，也许意大利的一些意大利人用面粉从头开始做意大利面，
and they knead it and they make everything from scratch.
他们揉面，一切都是从头开始。
Wow.
哇。
So you don't buy a box of spaghetti, but you actually have to cut the spaghetti and
所以你不买一盒意大利面，而是实际上要切意大利面并
pull it.
拉它。
Exactly.
正是。
Very, very hard work.
非常非常辛苦的工作。
So to make something from scratch.
所以是“从头开始做某物”。
And usually you can add the something goes in between, right?
通常你可以把某物加在中间，对吧？
To make lemonade from scratch, make bread from scratch.
从头开始做柠檬水，从头开始做面包。
Make ice cream from scratch.
从头开始做冰淇淋。
Okay.
好的。
So those are our three phrases for today.
所以这就是我们今天的三条短语。
Let's listen to the dialogue for one last time and we'll be back to talk about this
让我们最后听一遍对话，然后我们会回来讨论这个
very, very interesting topic.
非常非常有趣的话题。
Mother, father, I'd like to introduce you to my fiance, Bob.
妈妈，爸爸，我想向你们介绍我的未婚夫，鲍勃。
Hello, Bob.
你好，鲍勃。
Welcome.
欢迎。
Thanks for having me.
谢谢招待。
Uh, nice to meet the both of you.
呃，很高兴见到你们两位。
I've heard so much.
久仰大名。
So Cindy told you about bringing home her last boyfriend then.
所以辛迪告诉过你她带回家上一个男朋友的事？
That idiot.
那个白痴。
Shhh.
嘘。
Thurston, you're going to scare the poor boy.
瑟斯顿，你会吓到可怜的小伙子的。
Come in and have a drink.
进来喝一杯吧。
Dinner will be on in just a bit.
晚餐马上就好。
What will you be having?
你想喝什么？
Whiskey, bourbon, pick your poison.
威士忌、波本，随便选一个。
If you have a lemonade, that'd be great.
如果有柠檬水，那就太好了。
Lemonade?
柠檬水？
Why sure, there's some in the fridge.
当然有，冰箱里有一些。
Mother makes her own lemonade from scratch.
妈妈亲手做的柠檬水，从头开始做的。
It's the best.
最好喝了。
So, what are your hobbies, son?
那么，你有什么爱好，孩子？
If you want, we can do some hunting tomorrow.
如果你愿意，我们明天可以去打猎。
I've just picked up a new rifle I've been meaning to try out.
我刚弄到一把新步枪，一直想试试。
Should be a real hoot.
肯定特别好玩。
Um, I'm not really, uh, I don't really hunt.
嗯，我不太，呃，我不怎么打猎。
You don't hunt?
你不打猎？
Well, I'll be damned.
哎呀，真没想到。
Bob is an animal rights activist.
鲍勃是个动物权益活动家。
He doesn't believe in harming animals.
他不相信伤害动物。
Dinner's ready.
晚饭好了。
Let's go out to the patio where the pig is roasting.
我们去院子里吧，那里正在烤猪。
Roast pig?
烤猪？
I'm a vegetarian.
我是素食主义者。
This is a very scary topic for a lot of people.
这对很多人来说是个很吓人的话题。
I think they get very nervous introducing themselves because in this case, Bob is going
我觉得他们自我介绍时会很紧张，因为在这个情况下，鲍勃要
to be marrying Cindy.
和辛迪结婚。
So these are going to be his in-laws forever.
所以这些人将永远是他的岳父母。
Yeah, and it seems interesting, the differences, as you mentioned before, between the father-in-law
是啊，而且看起来很有趣，就像你之前提到的，岳父
who's very much into hunting and drinks and likes roast pig, whereas this guy is more
非常喜欢打猎、喝酒和烤猪，而这个人更
of an animal rights activist, doesn't drink.
像个动物权益活动家，不喝酒。
He's a vegetarian.
他是素食主义者。
And a vegetarian.
还是个素食主义者。
He doesn't eat meat.
他不吃肉。
So, I think it would be very complicated.
所以，我觉得这会很复杂。
And I think this happens a lot also with people from different cultures, right?
而且我觉得这也经常发生在不同文化的人身上，对吧？
Maybe you're Asian and you're marrying an American or something like this.
也许你是亚洲人，要和一个美国人结婚之类的。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
I think it can be very, very difficult.
我觉得这可能会非常非常困难。
I recently went to a wedding between a Chinese girl and an American guy, and it was amazing
我最近参加了一个中国女孩和美国小伙的婚礼，看到
to see all these people getting together because the families were so different.
所有这些聚在一起的人真是太棒了，因为两个家庭差异很大。
But they all got along really well.
但他们相处得非常好。
It was really fun.
真的很有趣。
They were all very supportive.
他们都非常支持。
They were just excited for their kids.
他们只是为孩子们感到兴奋。
Yeah, but I think it can be a little bit difficult, right?
是啊，但我觉得可能会有点困难，对吧？
I mean, being in a family where the culture is so different or the traditions and the
我的意思是，在一个文化如此不同、传统和
customs are strange to you.
习俗对你来说很陌生的家庭里。
But it's exciting because then as a family, the young people who are getting married,
但这也很令人兴奋，因为作为一家人，那些要结婚的年轻人，
they can pick the traditions they want and make new traditions.
他们可以选择自己喜欢的传统，并创造新的传统。
So this is a very interesting topic.
所以这是个非常有趣的话题。
We want to know, maybe if you are married, how did it go when you met your in-laws?
我们想知道，也许如果你结婚了，你第一次见岳父母时怎么样？
Are you very different?
你们差异很大吗？
Or did you get along very well?
还是相处得很好？
Or how is it in your country?
或者你们国家的情况是怎样的？
Yeah, please do let us know.
是啊，请告诉我们。
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
我们的网站是 EnglishPod.com。
We hope to see you there.
希望在那里见到你。
All right, everyone.
好了，各位。
Bye.
再见。
It looks like we've just gotta do our job.
看来我们得做好自己的工作了。